Howells family. Howells family papers (MS Am 1784-1784.13): Guide.
Howells family papers,
- V. bMS Am 1784.8-1784.10: The Mildred Howells Collection
  - A. bMS Am 1784.8: Correspondence of Mildred Howells
    - 2. Letters to Mildred Howells (gift)
      - Steele, Marjorie. 2 letters; 1923., (496)
      - Stevens, Robley D. 1 letter; 1938., (497)
      - Stevenson, Haviland. 2 letters; 1934., (498)
      - Stewart, D.M. 1 letter; 1938., (499)
      - Stidger, William Le Roy, 1886-. 1 letter; 1933., (500)
      - Stoddard, Charles Warren, 1843-1909. 3 letters; 1892-1894., (501)
      - Stoddard, Elizabeth Drew (Barstow) 1823-1902. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (502)
      - Stone, Clarence Robert, 1882-. 1 letter; 1925., (503)
        *43M-531
      - Strang, Bert D. 1 letter; 1933., (504)
      - Strobell, Caro (Lloyd). 1 letter; 1935., (505)
      - Sumstine, David R. 2 letters; 1935., (506)
      - Sutphen, F.T. 1 letter; 1933., (507)
      - Swope, Eugene. 2 letters; 1931., (508)
      - Tarkington, Booth, 1869-1946. 1 letter; 1910., (509)
        *44M-110
      - Thomas, W.E. 1 letter; 1926., (510)
      - Thomas, W.E. 2 letters; 1926., (511)
      - Thompson, D.D. 1 letter; 1930., (512)
      - Thorne, D. 2 letters; 1929., (513)
      - Thring, George Herbert, 1859-1941. 2 letters; 1928., (514)
        No. 2 lithographed.
      - Tong, Jocelyn. 1 letter; 1938., (515)
      - Towne, Charles Hanson, 1877-1949. 2 letters; 1924., (516)
      - Trilling, Lionel, 1905-. 3 letters; 1936., (517)
      - Truesdell, Cornelia Riggs. 1 letter; 1929., (518)
      - Ulery, C.B. 2 letters; 1936., (519)
      - Vanamee, Grace D. 4 letters; 1927-1928., (520)
        1-3: *54M-329
        4: *43M-788F
      - Van Dyke, Tertius, 1886-. 1 letter; 1935., (521)
      - Viljoen, Helen Gill. 5 letters; 1938-1939., (522)
      - Vonnoh, Bessie O. (Potter). 2 letters; 1906-1910., (523)
      - Wagstaff, W.H. 1 letter; 1921., (524)
      - Walker, Franklin, 1900-. 2 letters; 1931-1932., (525)
      - Wahl, C.L. 1 letter; 1928., (526)
      - Walter, Erich Albert. 1 letter; 1938., (527)
      - Walters, Maude (Owens) 1891-. 2 letters; 1929., (528)
      - Walton, William, 1843-1915. 1 letter; 1907., (529)
      - Wann, Louis, 1885-. 4 letters; 1926-1932., (530)
      - Ward, John Quincy Adams, 1830-1910. 1 letter; 1899., (531)
      - Warfel, Harry Redcay, 1899-. 1 letter; 1936., (532)
      - Watson, S.B. 3 letters; 1933-1934., (533)
        1: *58M-18
      - Wells, Thomas B. 2 letters; 1921., (534)
      - Werner, William Louser. 2 letters; 1938., (535)
      - White, Percy, 1852-. 1 letter; 1908., (536)
        *45M-328
      - White, William Allen, 1868-1944. 1 letter; 1937., (537)
      - Whitehead, Sara B. 1 letter; 1939., (538)
      - Whittemore, Bradford Adams. 1 letter; 1925., (539)
      - Wiggin, Kate Douglas (Smith) 1857-1923. 2 letters; [n.d.]., (540)
      - Williams, John L.B. 1 letter; 1937., (541)
      - Woodbury, Benjamin Collins, 1882-. 1 letter; 1929., (542)
      - Wormwood, R.F. 1 letter; 1923., (543)
      - Wright, Conrad, 1917-. 1 letter; 1936., (544)
      - Wyatt, Edith Franklin, 1873-1958. 6 letters; 1923-1941 [n.d.]., (545)
        1: *44M-117
        2: *44M-118
        3: *45M-527
        4: *54M-328
        5: *43M-565
        6: *45M-530
      - Yard, Joseph A. 1 letter; 1935., (546)
      - Unidentified. 4 letters; 1925 [n.d.]., (547)
  - B. bMS Am 1784.9: Letters from Mildred Howells
    Letters from Mildred Howells to various correspondents.
    - Abbott, Charles David, 1900-, addressee. 2 letters; 1925., (1)
    - Allen, Phillipa, addressee. 1 letter; 1930., (2)
    - Allen, William Charles, 1857-, addressee. 1 letter; 1929., (3)
    - American play company, New York, addressee. 1 letter; 1931., (4)
    - Archer, Charles, 1861-, addressee. 1 letter; [1930]., (5)
    - Arms, George Warren, 1912-, addressee. 2 letters; 1938-1943., (6)
    - Ayer, Dana S., addressee. 1 letter; 1920., (7)
    - Bacon, Russell M., addressee. 1 letter; 1937., (8)
    - Bailey, Carolyn Sherwin, 1875-, addressee. 1 letter; 1924., (9)
    - Baird, Theodore, addressee. 1 letter; 1930., (10)
    - Barrow, Hollie M., addressee. 1 letter; 1942., (11)
    - Bates, Herbert, 1868-1929, addressee. 1 letter; 1925., (12)
    - Beard, Charles Austin, 1874-1948, addressee. 2 letters; 1942., (13)
    - Belcher, Hannah Graham, addressee. 3 letters; 1943., (14)
    - Bennett, Paul A., 1897-, addressee. 2 letters; 1939., (15)
      No. 1 with two file copies; no. 2 is an autograph draft with a typed file copy.
    - Bewley, Luther B., addressee. 2 letters; 1938., (16)
    - Bingham, H.H., addressee. 1 letter; 1941., (17)
    - Bird, Esther Brock, addressee. 1 letter; 1924., (18)
    - Bolton, Frederick Elmer, 1866-, addressee. 2 letters; 1923-1931., (19)
    - Booth, F.G., addressee. 4 letters; 1937-1942., (20)
    - Boynton, Percy Holmes, 1875-, addressee. 1 letter; [1934]., (21)
    - Brammer, Mauck, addressee. 1 letter; 1925., (22)
    - Brandt and Brandt, New York, addressee. 1 letter; 1928., (23)
    - Briggs, Walter Benjamin, 1870-1943, addressee. 1 letter; 1927., (24)
    - Briggs, William Harlowe, addressee. 18 letters; 1923-1936., (25)
      No. 1 with copy in the hand of Mildred Howells of a letter from Charles H. Sergel to Frank W. Chandler.
      No. 6 with copy of a letter from Mildred Howells to J.C. Squire.
      2,8,9,11,12: *45M-531
      1,3-7,10: *45M-532
      13-18: *45M-534
    - Brown, Edmund R., addressee. 1 letter; 1930., (26)
    - Brummitt, E.P., addressee. 1 letter; 1931., (27)
    - Burrell, Angus, addressee. 1 letter; 1935., (28)
    - Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1947, addressee. 2 letters; 1931-1932., (29)
      No. 1 is a draft in the hand of Mildred Howells with a typed copy.
    - Cain, James Mallahan, 1892-, addressee. 2 letters; 1925., (30)
      No. 2 is a typed file copy with an extra carbon copy.
    - Canby, Henry Seidel, 1878-1961, addressee. 7 letters; 1926-1927., (31)
    - Cargill, Oscar, 1898-, addressee. 1 letter; 1941., (32)
    - Carmen, Ruth, addressee. 1 letter; 1935., (33)
    - Carroll, Margaret, 1899-, addressee. 1 letter; 1936., (34)
    - Cavanah, Frances, addressee. 1 letter; 1939., (35)
    - Cerf, Bennett Alfred, 1898-, addressee. 2 letters; 1935., (36)
    - Clark, Barrett Harper, 1890-1953, addressee. 2 letters; 1927-1928., (37)
    - Clemens, Clara, addressee. 2 letters; 1944., (38)
    - Cleveland, Ohio. William Dean Howells Junior High School, addressee. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (39)
      Draft with typed copy.
      *58M-17
    - Coe, Alice Rollit, addressee. 1 letter; 1926., (40)
    - Cohn, Janet, addressee. 1 letter; 1938., (41)
    - Collins, Seward B., addressee. 6 letters; 1928., (42)
      No. 1 with copy of a letter from Mildred Howells to [Russell] Doubleday.
      No. 4 is a typed copy, with two copies incorporating corrections by Mildred Howells.
      No. 6 with a second draft.
    - Columbia Book Publishing co., New York, addressee. 1 letter; 1939., (43)
    - Craig, John, addressee. 9 letters; 1928., (44)
    - Crofts, Frederick S., addressee. 1 letter; 1927., (45)
    - Cross, Ethan Allen, 1875-, addressee. 2 letters; 1934., (46)
    - Curry, Charles Madison, 1869-, addressee. 2 letters; 1939., (47)
    - Deming, Norma Helen, addressee. 1 letter; 1935., (48)
    - Derby, George, addressee. 1 letter; 1934., (49)
    - Doran, []. 1 letter; 1928., (50)
    - Doremus, Edwin, addressee. 1 letter; 1942., (51)
    - Doubleday, Russell, 1872-, addressee. 11 letters; 1925-[1937]., (52)
      Nos. 1, 5, and 7 are drafts in the hand of Mildred Howells with typed file copies.
      No. 2 with incomplete second copy.
      No. 7 with two additional drafts.
    - Doubleday, Russell, 1872-, addressee. 23 letters; 1925-1929., (53)
      No. 13 with two other drafts.
    - Downe, Mabel B., addressee. 1 letter; 1924., (54)
    - Dudley, Frank Elijah, addressee. 1 letter; 1935., (55)
    - Edbrooke, [E], addressee. 1 letter; 1939., (56)
    - Eidson, John Olin, 1908-, addressee. 1 letter; 1942., (57)
    - Elson, William Harris, 1856-1935, addressee. 3 letters; 1923., (58)
    - Elting, Mary, 1909-, addressee. 1 letter; 1934., (59)
    - Farma, William Joseph, addressee. 1 letter; 1930., (60)
    - Farrar, John, 1896-, addressee. 1 letter; 1928., (61)
    - Ferguson, John De Lancey, 1888-, addressee. 4 letters; 1937-[1943]., (62)
    - Field, Walter Taylor, 1861-, addressee. 1 letter; 1925., (63)
    - Fish, Eleanor, addressee. 2 letters; 1934., (64)
    - Fish, Helen Dean, addressee. 1 letter; 1923., (65)
      With draft of a letter from Mildred Howells to [William Harlowe] Briggs.
    - Fisher, Thomas K., addressee. 1 letter; 1924., (66)
    - Fitz-Gerald, John Driscoll, 1873-1946, addressee. 1 letter; 1924., (67)
    - Foerster, Norman, 1887-, addressee. 4 letters; 1929-1933., (68)
      1,4: *45M-531
      2,3: *45M-534
    - Frear, Walter Francis, 1863-, addressee. 2 letters; 1942-1943., (69)
    - Frederick, John Towner, 1893-, addressee. 4 letters; [1942]-1943., (70)
    - Fuess, Claude Moore, 1885-1963, addressee. 1 letter; 1929., (71)
    - Gagnot, B.M., addressee. 1 letter; 1925., (72)
    - Garrison, Curtis Wiswell, addressee. 1 letter; 1937., (73)
    - Gaston, Charles Robert, addressee. 1 letter; 1924., (74)
    - Gerould, James Thayer, 1872-, addressee. 1 letter; 1933., (75)
    - Ginn, firm, publishers, Boston, addressee. 3 letters; 1927., (76)
    - Godkin, M.C., addressee. 2 letters; 1925., (77)
    - Gohdes, Clarence Louis Frank, 1901-, addressee. 1 letter; 1943., (78)
    - Goodspeed, Charles Eliot, 1867-, addressee. 1 letter; 1936., (79)
    - Gray, Clarence Truman, addressee. 1 letter; 1928., (80)
    - Greenslet, Ferris, 1875-1959, addressee. 8 letters; 1927-1938., (81)
      1,6: *45M-533
      2-5: *45M-534
    - Halbeison, Elizabeth Kobus, 1904-, addressee. 1 letter; 1934., (82)
    - Halen, [], addressee. 1 letter; 1932., (83)
    - Hardin, Ivan Bloom, addressee. 1 letter; 1926., (84)
    - Harper, Wilhelmina, addressee. 2 letters; 1924-1926., (85)
    - Harper, firm, publishers, New York, addressee. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (86)
    - Hartwick, Harry, addressee. 2 letters; 1934., (87)
    - Hatfield, Walter Wilbur, 1882-, addressee. 1 letter; 1929., (88)
    - Heck, Chester R., addressee. 1 letter; 1934., (89)
    - Heiser, Alta (Harvey) 1877-, addressee. 1 letter; 1936., (90)
    - Hersey, Frank Wilson Cheney, 1876-, addressee. 1 letter; 1922., (91)
    - Hicks, Granville, 1901-, addressee. 2 letters; 1933., (92)
    - Hitchcock, Curtice, addressee. 1 letter; 1942., (93)
      Autograph draft with typed copy.
    - Horan, Kenneth (O'Donnell) 1890-, addressee. 1 letter; 1929., (94)
    - Horn, Mary A., addressee. 1 letter; 1924., (95)
    - Horrell, Joseph, addressee. 1 letter; 1938., (96)
    - Hosic, James Fleming, 1870-, addressee. 1 letter; 1924., (97)
    - Howe, Mark Antony DeWolfe, 1864-1960, addressee. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (97a)
    - Howe, Will David, 1873-, addressee. 3 letters; 1923-1929., (98)
    - Howells, John Mead, 1868-1959, addressee. 2 letters; 1925-1943., (99)
      No. 2 with notes by John Mead Howells.
      1: *45M-525
    - Hoyt, Franklin Sherman, addressee. 1 letter; 1934., (100)
    - Hubbell, Jay Broadus, 1885-, addressee. 1 letter; 1935., (101)
    - Hunter, Allen Armstrong, 1893-, addressee. 1 letter; 1924., (102)
    - Huntington, James Lincoln, addressee. 1 letter; [1935]., (103)
    - Inch, Eileen R., addressee. 2 letters; 1942., (104)
    - Inglis, Rewey Belle, 1885-, addressee. 1 letter; 1935., (105)
    - Irving, Beth, addressee. 2 letters; 1935., (106)
    - Jefferson, Bernard Levi, 1887-, addressee. 1 letter; 1929., (107)
    - Jenovese, Anne D., addressee. 1 letter; 1936., (108)
    - Jensen, Gerard Edward, 1884-, addressee. 1 letter; 1939., (109)
    - Johnson, Willis Fletcher, 1857-1931, addressee. 1 letter; 1929., (110)
    - Jones, Easley Stephen, 1884-, addressee. 1 letter; 1931., (111)
    - Jones, Patricia, addressee. 1 letter; 1943., (112)
    - Joseph, Nannine V., addressee. 1 letter; 1928., (113)
    - Keil, [Paul L.], addressee. 1 letter; 1929., (114)
    - Kilday, Elizabeth, addressee. 1 letter; 1930., (115)
    - Klingler, Ethel F., addressee. 1 letter; 1925., (116)
    - Knight, Pearle Ethel, addressee. 1 letter; 1932., (117)
    - Kraemer, Rose A., addressee. 1 letter; 1931., (118)
    - Lathrop, Henry Burrowes, 1867-, addressee. 1 letter; 1929., (119)
    - Leisy, Ernest Erwin, 1887-, addressee. 4 letters; 1934-[1939]., (120)
      No. 4 is draft with typed copy.
    - Lewis, Edward Rieman, 1886-, addressee. 1 letter; 1937., (121)
    - Lewis, Leo Rich, 1865-1945, addressee. 3 letters; 1935., (122)
    - Lieber, Maxim, addressee. 2 letters; 1925-1942., (123)
    - Loveman, Amy, 1881-1955, addressee. 1 letter; 1928., (124)
    - Mahan, Bruce Ellis, addressee. 1 letter; 1938., (125)
    - Manchester, Frederick Alexander, 1882-, addressee. 1 letter; 1925., (126)
    - Marbury, [], addressee. 1 letter; 1931., (127)
    - Marchand, Ernest, addressee. 1 letter; 1942., (128)
    - Marston, Frederic C., Jr., addressee. 1 letter; 1942., (129)
    - Martin, Earle, addressee. 1 letter; [1936]., (130)
    - Martin, Lorene, addressee. 1 letter; [1939]., (131)
      With recollections of Larkin G. Mead by Mabel C. Mead.
    - Mason, Kenneth Oliver, addressee. 1 letter; 1928., (132)
      Autograph draft with typed file copy.
    - Matteis, Maria de, addressee. 2 letters; 1929., (133)
    - Maynard, Carol, addressee. 1 letter; 1926., (134)
    - Meech, Sylvia, addressee. 1 letter; 1934., (135)
    - Mencken, Henry Louis, 1880-1956, addressee. 1 letter; 1934., (136)
    - Miles, Dudley Howe, 1881-, addressee. 1 letter; 1929., (137)
    - Millard, William Barrett, 1867-, addressee. 2 letters; 1927., (138)
    - Montel, Denise, addressee. 2 letters; 1931-1932., (139)
      No. 2 is autograph draft with typed file copy.
    - Mookerjee, Harendra Coomar, addressee. 1 letter; 1924., (140)
    - Morse, Edwin Wilson, 1855-, addressee. 1 letter; 1924., (140a)
    - Nordstrom, [], addressee. 1 letter; 1939., (141)
    - Noyes, Pierrepont Burt, 1870-, addressee. 1 letter; [1939]., (142)
    - Page, Mary C., addressee. 1 letter; 1939., (143)
    - Paine, Albert Bigelow, 1861-1937, addressee. 2 letters; 1925., (143a)
    - Park, John Edgar, 1879-, addressee. 1 letter; 1936., (144)
    - Pattee, Fred Lewis, 1863-, addressee. 1 letter; 1926., (145)
    - Peacock, Leishman Arnold, addressee. 1 letter; 1942., (146)
    - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1909-, addressee. 2 letters; 1935-1938., (147)
    - Pierce, (Mrs.) Louis Warren, addressee. 1 letter; 1931., (148)
    - Pinker, Eric S., addressee. 6 letters; 1928., (149)
      No. 6 with incomplete file copy.
    - Pinker, J. Ralph, addressee. 2 letters; 1928., (150)
    - Pooley, Robert Cecil, 1898-, addressee. 1 letter; 1935., (150a)
    - Pritchard, Francis Henry, 1884-, addressee. 1 letter; 1928., (151)
    - Punké, Edward G., addressee. 1 letter; 1930., (152)
    - Quinn, Arthur Hobson, 1875-, addressee. 3 letters; 1926-1936., (153)
      1: *54M-329
    - Randall, David, addressee. 1 letter; 1944., (154)
    - Rankin, Daniel S., 1895-, addressee. 1 letter; 1937., (155)
    - Rankin, Thomas Ernest, 1872-, addressee. 2 letters; 1924., (156)
    - Richardson, Lyon Norman, addressee. 3 letters; 1934., (157)
      No. 2 with copy of a contract between L.N. Richardson and the American Book Company.
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, addressee. 1 letter; 1928., (158)
    - Robins, Lillian M., addressee. 1 letter; 1942., (159)
    - Robins, Lillian M., addressee. 3 letters; 1928., (160)
    - Rockwell, Kenneth, addressee. 1 letter; 1937., (161)
    - Rosedale, Honyel Gough, 1863-1928, addressee. 1 letter; 1927., (161a)
    - Rowland, Sydney Vanferson, 1888-, addressee. 1 letter; 1927., (162)
    - Rusk, Ralph Leslie, 1888-, addressee. 1 letter; 1932., (163)
    - Salisbury, Leah, addressee. 3 letters; 1931-1932., (164)
    - Samuels, F.A.S., addressee. 1 letter; 1936., (165)
    - Schuler, Eric, addressee. 2 letters; 1924., (166)
    - Schuler, Eric, addressee. 7 letters; 1928., (167)
    - Schwarz, John, addressee. 1 letter; 1938., (168)
      *54M-529
    - Scott, Carrie Emma, addressee. 1 letter; 1933., (169)
    - Scribner, firm, publishers, New York, addressee. 2 letters; 1925., (169a)
    - Seaver, Edwin, 1900-, addressee. 3 letters; 1943., (169b)
    - Sergel, Charles Hubbard, addressee. 15 letters; [1923]-1925., (170)
      Nos. 4, 8 and 11 with a second autograph draft.
      No. 5 is a draft with two typed copies.
      No. 15 with a second typed copy.
    - Shafer, Robert, 1889-, addressee. 2 letters; 1926., (171)
    - Shapiro, Dorothy B., addressee. 1 letter; 1938., (172)
    - Sharp, Russell Alger, addressee. 1 letter; 1929., (173)
    - Shepard and Lawrence, inc., addressee. 1 letter; 1928., (174)
    - Shurter, Robert LeFevre, 1907-, addressee. 1 letter; 1935., (175)
    - Sillcox, Luise, addressee. 5 letters; 1932-[1938]., (176)
      1-4: *45M-534
      5: *45M-533
    - Sinclair, Robert B., addressee. 2 letters; 1939., (177)
    - Smart, Charles Allen, 1904-, addressee. 5 letters; 1928., (178)
    - Smith, Bernard, 1906-, addressee. 2 letters; 1941., (179)
    - Smith, Bertha W., addressee. 1 letter; 1931., (180)
    - Smith, Reed, 1881-, addressee. 1 letter; 1937., (181)
    - Smith, Thomas Robert, 1880-1933, addressee. 2 letters; 1924., (182)
      With draft of a letter from Mildred Howells to William Harlowe Briggs.
    - Snyder, Franklin Bliss, 1884-, addressee. 2 letters; 1925., (183)
      No. 1 is draft with typed copy.
    - Stidger, William Le Roy, 1886-, addressee. 1 letter; 1933., (184)
    - Stone, Clarence Robert, 1882-, addressee. 1 letter; 1925., (185)
    - Sumstine, David R., addressee. 1 letter; 1935., (186)
    - Swope, Eugene, addressee. 1 letter; 1931., (187)
    - Thomas, W.E., addressee. 1 letter; 1926., (188)
    - Towne, Charles Hanson, 1877-1949, addressee. 1 letter; 1921., (189)
    - Trilling, Lionel, 1905-, addressee. 2 letters; 1936-[1938]., (190)
    - Ulery, C.B., addressee. 1 letter; 1936., (191)
    - Viljoen, Helen Gill, addressee. 3 letters; 1938., (192)
    - Walker, Franklin, 1900-, addressee. 1 letter; 1932., (193)
    - Walter, Erich Albert, addressee. 1 letter; 1938., (194)
    - Walters, Maude (Owens) 1891-, addressee. 1 letter; 1929., (195)
    - Wann, Louis, 1885-, addressee. 2 letters; 1926-1932., (196)
    - Warfel, Harry Redcay, 1899-, addressee. 1 letter; 1936., (197)
    - Watson, S.B., addressee. 1 letter; 1933., (198)
    - Werner, William Louser, addressee. 1 letter; 1938., (199)
    - Whitlock, Brand, 1869-1934, addressee. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (199a)
      William Dean Howells Junior High School, Cleveland, Ohio, addressee. See Cleveland, Ohio, William Dean Howells Junior High School.
    - Williams, John L.B., addressee. 1 letter; 1937., (200)
    - Williamson, R.D., addressee. 1 letter; 1924., (201)
    - Wiswall, [], addressee. 1 letter; 1942., (202)
    - Woodbury, Benjamin Collins, 1882-, addressee. 2 letters; 1929., (203)
      No. 2 with second draft.
    - Yard, Joseph A., addressee. 1 letter; [1935]., (204)
  - C. bMS Am 1784.10: Compositions, drawings, and miscellaneous material from the Mildred Howells collection
    - Howells, Mildred, 1872-. Lines written by a young lady to her father, a celebrity, on the occasion of his absence in the West. A.MS.s.; [n.p., 1897], (1); 1s.(1p.)
      *58M-9
    - Howells, Mildred, 1872-. [Poems]. TS. (modern transcript, unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (2); 52s.(52p.)
      *59M-1
    - Howells, Mildred, 1872-. Travel diaries. [v.p., v.d.], (3); 3v.
    - Howells, Mildred, 1872-. Notebooks used in preparation for Life in letters; [n.p., n.d.], (4); 8v.
    - Howells, Mildred, 1872-. [[Life in letters of William Dean Howells]. TS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (5); 3 boxes.
      Boxes 2 and 3 contain material cut from the text at various stages and never published.
      box 1: Received, Jun. 1948
      boxes 2,3: *59M-1
    - Howells, Mildred, 1872-. [[Life in letters of William Dean Howells]. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (6); 6s.(6p.)
      Notes for chapter headings.
    - Howells, Mildred, 1872-. [Life in letters of William Dean Howells: Chapter I]. TS. (signed); [n.p., n.d.], (7); 10s.(10p.)
      Contains first part of Chapter I, p.1-12. With autograph revision.
    - Howells, Mildred, 1872-. [Life in letters of William Dean Howells: Preface]. TS. (carbon copy, unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (8); 14s.(14p.)
      With a letter from John Mead Howells to Mildred Howells, and with autograph revisions by John Mead Howells.
    - Howells, Mildred, 1872-. [Notes made in preparation for Life in letters...] [v.p., v.d.], (9); 2 folders.
    - Howells, Mildred, 1872-. [Publisher's contract for Life in letters of William Dean Howells]. TS. (carbon copy, unsigned); New York, 1925., (10); 3s.(3p.)
    - Howells, Mildred, 1872-. [Selections from the letters of William Dean Howells]. TS. (carbon copy, signed); [n.p., n.d.], (11); 27s.(27p.)
      Published in The Bookman (1928).
    - Howells, Mildred, 1872-. [List of correspondence of William Dean Howells published in The bookman, June 1928]. TS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (12); 6s.(6p.)
    - Howells, Mildred, 1872-. [Notices of pictures for "Le lynx"] Paris, 1896., (13); 2 pieces.
    - Howells, Mildred, 1872-. [Contract (signed) between Mary E. Burtt, Mildred Howells and Charles Scribner's sons for The literary primer]. New York, 25 Mar. 1901., (14); 2s.(3p.)
      *45M-529
    - Howells, Mildred, 1872-. [Proposed contract between Mildred Howells, John Mead Howells and the Dramatic Publishing company]. TS. (unsigned); [n.p., 1924], (15); 2s.(2p.)
      Annotated by Mildred Howells.
    - Howells, Mildred, 1872-. [Book-jacket design for Harriet Ross Colquitt's The Savannah cook book.] [New York, 1932]., (16)
      Mounted and matted for framing.
      *45M-535F
    - Howells, Mildred, 1872-. [Pen and ink sketches (unsigned); n.p., n.d.], (17); 40 items.
      Accepted by Houghton Mifflin company as illustrations for a volume of verse; never published.
    - Howells, Mildred, 1872-. [Drawing: William Dean Howells]. Pencil sketch (unsigned); Miami, 1919., (18)
    - Howells, Mildred, 1872-. Four photographs of watercolour drawings of Indians. [n.p., n.d.], (19); 1 folder.
    - Howells, Mildred, 1872-. [3 portrait photographs; Venice, 1883]., (20)
      At the time of Mildred Howells' drawings, A little girl among the old masters.
      *59M-257
    - Howells, Mildred, 1872-. [Portrait photograph; New York, 18 Feb. 1897], (21)
      *45M-536
    - Howells, Mildred, 1872-. [Scrapbook of clippings of writings and illustrations by Mildred Howells. n.p., v.d.], (22); 1v.
    - Howells, Mildred, 1872-. [Cuttings from newspapers and periodicals of poems and illustrations by Mildred Howells and other miscellaneous printed matter]. [v.p., v.d.], (23); 2 folders.
    - Howells, Mildred, 1872-. [Cuttings of reviews in newspapers and periodicals of Life in letters of William Dean Howells. v.p.] 1929., (24); 1 folder.
      *45M-526
    - Howells, Mildred, 1872-. [Sheet music: songs with lyrics by Mildred Howells. v.p., v.d.], (25); 4 pieces.
- VI. bMS Am 1784.11: The John Mead Howells Collection
  - A. Letters to John Mead Howells (purchase)
    Letters to John Mead Howells from various correspondents.
    - Channon, Vesta Westover. 1 letter; 1929., (1)
    - Howe, Mark Antony DeWolfe, 1864-1960. 1 letter; 1920., (2)
    - Monsarrat, Jean. 1 letter to her brother, John Grant Mitchell; [1928 Nov.]., (3)
      Letter forwarded to Mildred Howells. Formerly thought to be sent to John Mead Howells. Incomplete. For additonal information see: bMS Am 1784.8 (66).
    - North, Ernest Dressel. 1 letter; 1928., (4)
  - B. Letters to John Mead Howells (gift)
    - Aldrich, Richard, 1863-1937. 1 letter; 1929., (5)